aaamidatlantic.com 2011-06-29

# Privacy Policy - AAA - AAA Mid-Atlantic

## Privacy Policy

AAA Mid-Atlantic (and its affiliated insurance companies, insurance agency and travel agency) considers your privacy important to you and to us. In order to provide you with individualized service, we collect certain information about you (such as your name, address, date of birth, transactions with us) from information you provide on applications or other forms. We may also collect such information through your inquiries by e-mail or on our website.

 **Following are descriptions of how we treat the information you provide to us for various purposes.**

  * What We Collect Online
  * Use of Your Email Address
  * You May "Opt Out" of Offerings by Mail or Telephone
  * Information Collected from Non-Website Transactions with You
  * We Safeguard Your Information
  * Linking from AAA.com to Other Websites
  * Our use of cookies online

## What We Collect Online

For each visitor to our Web page, our Web server automatically recognizes the consumer's domain name. We collect that information on visitors to our website, the email addresses of those who communicate with us via email, aggregate information on what pages visitors access or visit and user-specific information on what pages visitors access. We also collect information volunteered by those visiting us online, such as survey information, applications for membership and requests for member services.

Return to Top

## Use of Your Email Address

The information we collect is used to improve the content of our web site and may be used to notify members and customers about benefit updates, special savings or other opportunities. We will only send you email if you have provided your email address to us through our website or by offering it to one of our AAA employees. If you wish to opt out of receiving email regarding offers of products and services from AAA Mid-Atlantic in the future, please let us know by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link within the email that you received from us. We will promptly recognize your preference and discontinue sending future email.

Return to Top

## You May "Opt Out" of Receiving Offerings by Mail or Telephone

We are aware that our members and customers may have differing views on receiving our offers of products and services. If you do not want to receive such offers, click here for an "opt out form", print, complete and mail to: AAA Mid-Atlantic, Corporate Marketing Department, One River Place, Wilmington, DE 19801. Please allow six to eight weeks for the suppression of your name from our lists to become effective. AAA members will continue to receive the Club publication, AAA World, on a bimonthly basis.

Return to Top

## Information Collected from Non-Website Transactions with You

Information we receive in the AAA Mid-Atlantic club and travel agency:

We do not share any information about you with anyone outside our affiliated companies for solicitation purposes, except preferred travel partners, our AAA Show Your Card & Save Program participants, and other companies that provide goods and services endorsed by AAA Mid-Atlantic. We only share your information in this way to offer you products and services that best meet your interests and needs and to effect transactions that you authorize or request. The companies outside our own affiliates will use this information only to promote their services to you and are not permitted to share your information or to use it for any other purpose.

Information we receive in our affiliated insurance companies, insurance agency and in connection with financial services - Nonpublic personal information is defined by law as any personal information about you that we obtain from you or others as part of your purchase or our delivery to you of insurance or a financial product, such as an auto loan. Nonpublic personal information may include your name, address, date of birth, and details of coverages, claims and payment history, and financial transactions with us, our affiliates or others. Whenever we share nonpublic personal information with others, we require them by written agreement to keep your information confidential and secure.

Use of Your nonpublic personal information - We will only use or disclose your nonpublic personal information for the following specific purposes. If you apply for insurance coverage from one of our insurance companies, we will collect and exchange the necessary information from your application, your agent, Bureaus of Motor Vehicles, fraud reporting agencies, claim index bureaus, current and prior insurers, finance companies and credit information with consumer reporting agencies in order to issue a policy.

We share nonpublic personal information with others only to deliver insurance services (such as authorizing repairs or defending an insurance claim), to provide information to reinsurers and government agencies who may examine our procedures, and as required by law. We may also share nonpublic personal information with other AAA Clubs or financial institutions under joint marketing agreements and with companies that help us develop and market insurance or financial products. At your request, we may disclose to others that you have insurance with one of our companies.

Return to Top

## We Safeguard Your Information

We also have internal security practices to safeguard the information we have about you. We restrict access to all of your personal and account information to those employees who need to know that information in order to serve you. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect your information, we monitor who has access to our databases, and we reinforce the privacy practices described here to our employees.

Return to Top

## Linking From AAA.com to Other Websites

Please remember that when you use a link to go away from the AAA Mid-Atlantic or AAA World web site, our privacy policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing, use or disclosure of your email address and other personal information, and interaction on any other website, including sites to which you can link from our site, are subject to the terms, conditions, and privacy policies of those sites. Please read those privacy policies carefully before proceeding.

## Our use of cookies online

What are cookies? Cookies are small pieces of information that a Web site transfers to your computer's hard drive for record-keeping and other purposes. Cookies make navigating the web easier for you by saving your registration, passwords, and references while you're at a site. By using cookies, we can serve you better since they help us understand what information interests you. We can then provide you more of the goods and services you like and want from us and our partners.

The use of cookies is an industry standard - most major Web sites use them. Cookies come in two types that might be used on our Web site: a persistent cookie and a session cookie. A persistent cookie gets entered by your Web browser in the "Cookies" folder on your computer and remains in this folder after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. A session cookie is help temporarily in your computer's memory and disappears after you close your browser or shut off your computer.

 **Here are some examples of how we use cookies:**

A cookie lets our computers remember that you've registered, which allows us to speed up your future activities at our Web site. Using cookies to do this record keeping saves you the trouble of entering information over and over again. We also use cookies to estimate the number of visitors to our Web site, track visits to and sales at the sites referenced on our Web site, and analyze our members' and customers' visiting patterns. Similarly, cookies help us tailor our product and service offerings, and those of our partners, to suit your personal interests.

We do not use cookies to store any of your personal or financial information on your computer. Also, we do not use cookies to retrieve information from your computer that was not originally provided by you or provided by your browser in a visit to our Web site. In addition, we do not use cookies to track other sites that you visit on the Internet.

We permit other approved companies to use a cookie when you visit our Web site to help us gather data to improve your shopping experience. Some of these approved companies may also use a cookie to show you information on products and services which might interest you. The use of such cookies sent by third-party servers is standard on the Internet. As mentioned above, we only share non-personally identifiable information in this way so these partners may bring you targeted offers. This information can be associated with their cookies but will not include personally identifiable information such as your name or address. You may review our partners' privacy policies when visiting their sites.

Once you visit or link to a partner's Web site, their sites may use cookies. We do not control those cookies and they are not subject or our cookies policy. 

**What to do if you do not want cookies used:**  
If you do not want cookies used in connection with your visit, or if you wish to limit their use, you can generally adjust your browser settings on your computer. Most Internet browsers allow you to set your own preferences for use of cookies. Please see the cookie security options in your browser and change them to suit your preferences. For example, you typically can either refuse to accept cookies or you can set your browser to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it. However, if you decline cookies, you may have difficulty navigating our Web site, which could adversely impact your AAA on-line experience.

Return to Top
